ASEFAW MEKURIA

120 Beach 19th Street | Far Rockaway, NY 11691 | (347) 876-3245 https://github.com/asefaw | Asefaw.Mekuria@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Goal driven and professional software and database developer with a solid understanding of Object- Oriented design and programming across multiple platforms. Who specializes in Oracle and Java technologies. Capable and always willing to learn new technologies. Highly organized and resourceful, coupled with effective multitasking skills and ability to accomplish projects under demanding and deadline-driven environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

Programming Languages: Java (Proficient), JSP (Proficient), PL/SQL (Proficient), JavaScript (Intermediate),

Visual basic (Beginner), ASP.Net (Beginner), RUBY (Beginner), PHP (Beginner)

Web Frame Works: Spring MVC, Rails, Hibernate

EDUCATION

New York City College of Technology – CUNY, Brooklyn, NY

Expected Graduation: December 2016

Bachelor of Arts

Major: Computer Systems Technology Concentration: Software Development

Cumulative GPA: 3.8/4.0

Dean's List: Spring 2015 (3.9), Fall 2015 (4.0) Spring 2016 (3.8)

The National Society of Collegiate Scholars 2015

EXPERIENCE

CUNY Codes Portfolio Development Program, New York, NY

10/2015 - 12/2016

Software Developer

- Developed a dynamic PHP application backed by MySQL
- Implemented secure login and authentication
- Implemented input validation method to avoid SQL injection
- Used agile development process

Research foundation of CUNY, New York, NY

10/2015 - Present

Help Desk Technician

- Provide first line technical support for HRA employees in person, via email and phone
- Determine the most effective manner to resolve client's technical issue.
- Engages in research and in-depth troubleshooting to resolve technical issues

Family Dollar, Rockaway Beach, NY

10/2014 - Present

Customer Service Representative

- Build sustainable relationships of trust through open and interactive communication
- Listen and respond to customers' needs and concerns
- Provide information about products and services

SamtaK Computers, Far Rockaway, NY

1/2011 - 6/2014

Computer Technician

- Worked on variety of equipment and platforms
- Dealt with different types customers in a professional manner
- Diagnosed and troubleshot technical problems onsite and remotely

PERSONAL PROJECTS

JobNet Job Searching Site, Far Rockaway, NY

06/2016 - Present

Lead Developer

- Currently Developing a Java web application using Spring Web MVC frame work
- The application has features such as posting jobs, searching, and applying for jobs
- Using Oracle database 12C and using Stored procedures

Hotel Management System, Far Rockaway, NY

10/2015 - 05/2016

Lead Developer

- Developed a Java Swing Application with features of checking in, out and payment.
- Designed and Implemented Oracle Database for backend
- Used Stored procedures for better performance

Airline Reservation System, Brooklyn, NY

02/2016 - 06/2016

Full stack Developer

- Developed a JSP web application for an airline reservation system as part of school project
- Designed and implemented Oracle Database to be used as backend
- Used stored procedures